Guide to the Edwin Dwight Northrup papers, [ca. 1820-1960]
Northrup, Edwin Dwight papers, [ca. 1820-1960]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Edwin Dwight Northrup papers, [ca. 1820-1960]
4190
Edwin Dwight. Northrup
48 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, legal papers, and financial records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal correspondence, diaries, legal papers, and financial records of Northrup, c.1870-1919, and his predecessor, lawyer and land agent William Samuel Johnson, c.1820-1897, both of Ellicottville, N.Y. Also correspondence and financial records of L. Ellen Northrup and Mrs. Elvena D. Northrup about the Northrup Style Shoppe, c.1890-1960, and correspondence with Eugene Debs, Theodore Debs, and Emma Goldman concerning socialism, women's rights, and other topics.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lawyer.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal correspondence, diaries, legal papers, and financial records of Northrup, c.1870-1919, and his predecessor, lawyer and land agent William Samuel Johnson, c.1820-1897, both of Ellicottville, N.Y. Also correspondence and financial records of L. Ellen Northrup and Mrs. Elvena D. Northrup about the Northrup Style Shoppe, c.1890-1960, and correspondence with Eugene Debs, Theodore Debs, and Emma Goldman concerning socialism, women's rights, and other topics.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Northrup, Edwin Dwight.; Debs, Eugene V.(Eugene Victor), 1855-1926.; Debs, Theodore, 1864-1945.; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940.; Johnson, William Samuel.; Northrup, Elvena D.; Northrup, L. Ellen.; Northrup Style Shoppe.
Subjects:
Socialism.; Women--Suffrage.; Women's rights.; Lawyers.
Places:
Ellicottville (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence: William Samuel Johnson tax notices, other legal documents, mostly re: land; W.S. Johnson ca. 1820, ca. 1840 (Box 1)
- Land ledger, 1850s-1860s (Box 1)
- Day book, Johnsons land office, 1892-1909 (Box 1)
- Shaffer farm acct. book, 1865 (Box 1)
- Wm. Samuel Johnson's financial journal, 1878-1897 (Box 1)
- Wm. Samuel Johnson's financial journal, 1861-1877 (Box 1)
- Johnsons land office ledger, 1865-1897 (Box 1)
- Ellen Northrup: correspondence, bills, receipts, etc. embroidery business, Ellicottville, N.Y., ca. 1900-1930 (Box 1)
- Letterbooks--Edwin D. Northrup, 1867-1916 (Box 2-6)
- The Credit Foncier of Sinaloa, 2 vols., 1887-1892 (Box 6)
- Legal documents (Box 7-13)
- Correspondence (Box 14)
- Legal documents (Box 15)
- Correspondence (Box 16)
  Contains material regarding 154th regiment.
- Legal documents (Box 17)
- Ellen Northrup correspondence, bills, etc. (Box 18)
- Legal documents (Box 19-24)
- Correspondence (Box 25)
- Correspondence (Box 26)
- Ellen Northrup (Box 27)
- Correspondence (Box 28-29)
- Legal documents (Box 30)
- Correspondence (Box 31)
- Legal documents (Box 32-33)
- Correspondence--contains Deb, Sanger, Flynn (Box 34)
- Correspondence (Box 35)
- ? (Box 36)
- Diaries--58 vols., 1858-1919 (Box 37)
- Justice docket, Ellicottville, 1875-1878, 1900 (Box 38)
- Account books, Samuel William Johnson ledger, 1853-1894 (Box 38)
- Legal documents (Box 39)
- Northrup Hyle Shop, Ellen Northrup, Mrs. J. King Northrup (Box 40)
- Legal and land ledger, 1903 (Box 41)
- Grocers accounts day book, 1903 (Box 41)
- Letterbook, 1883 (Box 41)
- D.G. Bingham day book, 1853-1861 (Box 41)
- Wm. Samuel Johnson land book, 1850-1896 (Box 42)
- Wm. Samuel Johnson acct. balance (2 vols.), 1857-1980 (Box 42)
- E.D. Northrup register (2 vols.), 1857-1917 (Box 42)
- E.D. Northrup court depositions (2 vols.), 1857-1917 (Box 42)
- Northrup acct. book, 1858-1882 (Box 42)
- Northrup subscription acct. book (Box 42)
- Northrup N.Y. Weekly World, 1860-1872 (Box 42)
- List of land grantees, 1854-1908 (Box 42)
- Memoranda and accts., 1865-1914 (Box 42)
- Northrup day book, 1885-1902 (Box 42)
- Misc. (Box 43)
- Financial (Box 43)
- Personal (Box 43)
- Edwin D. Northrup, corresp.; Mrs. J. King Northrup, 1920s-1930s (Box 44)